guys this looks like a fun one one thing
I'm definitely not going to do is
multiply x minus five out five times or
with this one or this one there has to
be a workaround so first we're going to
use the fact that a to the x times B to
the x is equal to a b to the X so this
to the 5 times this to the 5 is just
this times this to the 5. now we can
also use the property that's C to the d
e is equal to C to the D to the E that
means we're going to rewrite x minus 2
to the 10 as x minus 2 to the 2 to the
5. the cool thing about this is we now
have something to the fifth and
something to the fifth so we can take
the fifth root of both sides this fifth
root and this five will cancel which
means that we now have x minus 5 times X
plus four equals x minus 2 squared and
we can rewrite the x minus 2 squared as
x minus 2 times x minus 2. now we could
just multiply these out x times x is x
squared x times 4 is 4X negative 5 times
x is negative 5x and negative 5 times 4
is negative 20. and this is going to be
equal to x times x which is x squared x
times negative 2 which is negative 2x
negative 2 times x which is negative 2X
and negative 2 times negative 2 which is
positive 4. both sides of the equation
have a single x squared term so I'm
going to subtract that away and then for
the remaining stuff let's combine like
terms 4X minus 5x is negative X and
let's bring down the negative 20 and
this will be equal to negative 2x
negative 2x is negative 4X and bring
down the 4. we now have X on both sides
of the equation let's try to get all the
X's to the left hand side so we're going
to add 4X to both sides and I want to
get X alone on one side so I don't want
this 20 here so I'm going to add 20 to
both sides the negative 20 and the 20
are going to cancel each other out so
we're just left with negative X Plus 4X
which is equal to 3x and then this
negative 4X and positive 4X get rid of
each other so we're just left with 24 on
the right hand side after we divide both
sides by 3 we get X is equal to 8 and
that is the answer to the question we
can put a box around it let's check the
answer make sure it works so let's copy
this down from the top and let's plug in
8 for each of those X's 8 minus 5 is
equal to 3 and 8 plus 4 is equal to 12.
8 minus 2 is equal to 6. so here's
another example of a to the x times B to
the x that we could just rewrite as a b
to the X so this could become 3 times 12
on the inside which changes into 36 and
36 is equal to 6 squared and then we can
multiply these exponents we get 6 to the
10 and now we have 6 to the 10th power
equals 6 to the 10th power it checks out
how exciting